(301)531-0487 College Park, Maryland tsimosyiorgos@gmail.com

Georgios Tsimos

PhD Student in Cryptography

Website LinkedIn: gtsimos

I am a **Graduate Research Assistant** at the **Electrical Engineering** Department of the **University of Maryland** and a **PhD Student** at the **Maryland Cybersecurity Center** (MC2 Lab). My PhD advisor is Professor **Charalampos Papamanthou**. I am **interested in** several aspects of **Applied Cryptography**, some of which include **Consensus**, **Blockchains**, **Private Information Retrieval**, **Vector Commitment Schemes** and more. I am experienced in Protocols for **Byzantine Agreement/Authenticated Broadcast**. **Ongoing Research Projects:**

New techiques for **synchronous Broadcast** (with J. Loss and C. Papamanthou) and **Efficient Chain validation in Blockchains** (with I. Miers and C. Papamanthou). Also interested in the Theory of Cryptography, Algorithms and Computational Complexity.

EDUCATION

PhD Student in ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Aug 2019- Present

University of Maryland, College Park

Advisor: Professor Charalampos Papamanthou (at Yale)

Selected Coursework: Secure Distributed Computation (J. Katz), Advanced Cryptography and Hostile Governments (I. Miers), Cryptography (C. Papamanthou), Computer Security (T. Dumitras), Random Processes in Communications and Controls (B.

Babadi), Information Theory (P. Narayan)
Master's of Science in Computer Science

Oct 2018- July 2019 GPA: 9.44/10.0 (Honors)

Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece Bachelor's (4-year Ptychion) in COMPUTER SCIENCE

Oct 2014 - Sept 2018

Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece

GPA: 8.79/10.0 (Honors, Valedict.)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant

Aug. 2019 — Present

Maryland Cybersecurity Center (MC2 Lab)

University of Maryland, College Park, MD

- Research Focus 1: Adaptively Secure Consensus Protocols in Synchronous Networks.
- Research Focus 2: Randomized Protocols for Efficient Blockchain Validity Checks.

Undergraduate/Graduate Research Assistant

Mar. 2017 — Jun. 2019

Advisor: Assistant Prof. Eugenie Foustoucos

Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece

- Research Focus 1: Model Theory and Euhrenfeucht-Fraïssé Games of Logic
- Research Focus 2: Languages of Propositional and Mathematical Logic for expressing Complexity Classes

PUBLICATIONS

G. Tsimos and J. Loss and C. Papamanthou:

New!

"Gossiping For Communication-Efficient Broadcast"

CRYPTO' 2022

G. Tsimos: Thesis for completion of MS in Computer Science, at AUEB "A Comparative Research between the relation of various Satisfiability Problems and Complexity Classes"

HONORS AND AWARDS

DEAN'S FELLOWSHIP Aug. 2019 — Jun. 2020

for the First Year of Ph.D.

University of Maryland, College Park, MD

AWARD IN MEMORY OF MICHALIS MITILINAIOS

2016- 2017

for especially High Performance in the courses "Automata and Complexity", Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece "Logic" and "Computability and Complexity"

SKILLS

OS & Tools Linux, Windows, MacOS, Git

Programming Languages Golang, Java, Python (experienced)/ C, C++, Python, R, Matlab, HTML, CSS (familiar)

Communication English (fluent speaker), Greek (native), Spanish (basic communication)

VOLUNTARY ACTIVITIES AND SERVICE TO THE COMMUNITY

Udemy Course: "Go: The Complete Developer's Guide (Golang)"

Summer'21 - present

External Subreviewer for EuroCrypt21

Fall 2020

REFERENCES

Associate Professor Charalampos (Babis) Papamanthou (at Yale), (Ph.D Advisor):

charalampos.papamanthou@yale.edu

Assistant Professor Eugenie Foustoucos (at AUEB), (Master's Advisor, Bachelor's Thesis Advisor):

eugenie@aueb.gr

Assistant Professor Julian Loss (at CISPA), (Research Collaborator):

lossjulian@gmail.com

Assistant Professor Ian Miers (at UMD), (Research Collaborator):

imiers@umd.edu